<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Continents, Oceans and Deserts</string>

    <string name="title_activity_fullscreen">FullscreenActivity</string>
    <string name="splash_screen"> Continents and Oceans</string>
    <string name="dummy_content">DUMMY\nCONTENT</string>
    <string name="you_are_here">You are in</string>
    <string name="button1">Continents</string>
    <string name="button2">Oceans</string>
    <string name="next_button">next</string>
    <string name="finish_button">finish</string>
    <string name="prev_button">prev</string>
    <string name="Welcome_spash">Explore all the Continents \n Oceans and Deserts. </string>
    <string name="splash_image">splash image</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Share</string>
    <string name="sliderImage">slider</string>
    <string name="recimage">recima</string>
    <string name="oceanAction">Oceans</string>
    <string name="title_activity_next2">nextActivity2</string>
    <string name="indianocean">itis good</string>
    <string name="southernocean"> it is cold</string>
    <string name="continentsdefenition">Planet Earth is home to 7.3 billion people and over 1.5 million different species of animals, insects, and plants spread across 7 continents.
        Earth was not always comprised on seven continents. 175 million years ago the 7 continents were all connected into one supercontinent surrounded by a very large ocean. This supercontinent is known as Pangaea.
        \n\nIt slowly began to break apart into 7 different pieces and drift into the positions we find them in the present. But, the continents are not at rest.
        They are always moving and over time will move and drift into entirely new continents over the next several hundred million years.</string>

    <string name="what_is_continent">Though there are many definitions of the term “continent,” it is generally used to identify large distinct land masses that make up planet Earth’s surface.
        \n\nWhat we know as land are actually the areas which happen to be at a high enough elevation to not be flooded by the lakes, rivers, and oceans of the world which surround them.
        \n\nThe continents shapes and boundaries are ever-changing as the water surrounding them defines the land that makes up the continent. It is important to remember the five oceans of the world, as the continents make up just 1/3rd of Earth’s surface.</string>


    <string name="pacificOceantext">The Pacific Ocean is the body of water between Asia and Australia in the west,
        the Americas in the east, the Southern Ocean to the south, and the Arctic Ocean to the north. It is the largest named ocean and it covers one-third of the surface of the entire world.
        It joins the Atlantic Ocean at a line drawn south from Cape Horn, Chile/Argentina to Antarctica, and joins the Indian Ocean at a line drawn south from Tasmania, Australia to Antarctica.

As the Atlantic slowly gets wider, the Pacific is slowly shrinking. It does this by folding the sea floor in towards the center of the Earth - this is called subduction.
        This bumping and grinding is hard so there are many earthquakes and volcanoes when the pressure builds up and is quickly released as large explosions of hot rocks and dust.
        When an earthquake happens under the sea, the quick jerk causes a tsunami. This is why tsunamis are more common around the edge of the Pacific than anywhere else.
        Many of the Earth's volcanoes are either islands in the Pacific, or are on continents within a few hundred kilometers of the ocean's edge. Plate tectonics are another reason which makes Pacific Ocean smaller.</string>
    <string name="atlantistxt">Earth\'s oceans (World Ocean) Atlantic Ocean.png Atlantic Ocean Arctic Ocean Indian Ocean Pacific Ocean Southern Ocean View from Nantucket, Massachusetts The Atlantic Ocean is the world\'s second largest ocean.
        It covers a total area of about 106,400,000 square kilometres (41,100,000 square miles).[1] It covers about 20 percent of the Earth\'s surface.[1] It is named after the god Atlas from Greek mythology. Its name means</string>
    <string name="southerntxt">The Southern Ocean is the ocean around Antarctica. It was a new term in geography officially created in 2000. It means the waters of the Atlantic, Pacific,
        and Indian Oceans around the continent of Antarctica out to sixty degrees south latitude.
        Some people call this ocean the Antarctic Ocean.
        The total area is 20,327,000 km², and the coastline length is 17,968 km.</string>
    <string name="arctictxt">Earth\'s oceans (World Ocean) Arctic Ocean.png Atlantic Ocean Arctic Ocean Indian Ocean Pacific Ocean Southern Ocean Arctic Ocean and the surrounding lands The Arctic Ocean is the ocean around the North Pole.
        The most northern parts of Eurasia and North America are around the Arctic Ocean.
        Thick pack ice and snow cover almost all of this ocean in winter, and most of it in summer. An icebreaker or a nuclear-powered submarine can use the Northwest Passage through the Arctic Ocean to go between the Pacific and Atlantic oceans.
        The ocean\'s area is about 14.056 million km2, which is the smallest of the world\'s 5 oceans,
        and it has 45,389 kilometres (28,203 miles) of coastline. The central surface covered by ice about 3 metres (9.8 feet) thick. The biology there is quite special. Endangered species there include walruses, whales and polar bears.
        Year by year the Arctic ocean is becoming less icy, as a result of global warming.
        The average depth of the Arctic Ocean is 1,038 metres (3,406 feet).[1] The deepest point is in the Eurasian Basin, at 5,450 m (17,881 ft).</string>
    <string name="indianoceantxt">Earth\'s oceans (World Ocean) Indianocean.PNG Atlantic Ocean Arctic Ocean Indian Ocean Pacific Ocean Southern Ocean The Indian Ocean is the ocean surrounded by Asia to the north,
        Australia and the Pacific Ocean to the east, the Southern Ocean to the south, and Africa and the Atlantic Ocean to the west. It is named for the river Indus and Ancient India on its north shore. The Bay of Bengal, the Arabian Sea,
        the Persian Gulf and the Red Sea are all parts of this ocean. The deepest point in the Indian Ocean is in the Java Trench near the Sunda Islands in the east, 7500 m (25,344 feet) deep. The average depth is 3,890 m (12,762 ft).
        The Indian Ocean is the third largest ocean, 28,350,000 square miles in size. The majority is in the southern hemisphere.</string>
    <string name="button3">Deserts</string>
    <string name="antarcticadesert">Conversely, the name Antarctica derives from a Greek word meaning “opposite to the arctic” or “opposite to the north,” which is a rather textbook description given that it is the southernmost continent on Earth. Not unsurprisingly, Antarctica contains the geographic South Pole. It lies almost entirely south of the Antarctic Circle and is surrounded by the Southern Ocean. It is the fifth largest continent in the world, covering more than 5,400,000 square miles (14,000,000 square kilometers). That’s 1.3 times the size of Europe! Almost 98 percent of Antarctica is covered in ice that averages 1.2 miles (1.9 kilometers) in thickness, which accounts for 90% of the world’s ice and 70% of the world’s fresh water. Considered a desert climate, Antarctica has an annual precipitation of only 8 inches (200 millimeters) near the coast and much less when venturing further inland. Antarctica is extremely cold – the coldest continent on Earth – with temperatures reaching as low as -129°F (-89°C)! There is no evidence of an indigenous population in Antarctica, and to this day, there are no permanent human residents (though there are scientists who bravely face the cold in the name of science!). But life still endures from algae and bacteria to animals like penguins and seals</string>
    <string name="saharadesert">Of the deserts of the world, the Sahara Desert is the largest desert that falls into a sub-tropical climate. The Sahara covers most of northeastern Africa which is about 10% of the continent. It is nearly as large as the United States in terms of land area. It can take upwards of a week to cross this desert by car and more than 40 days walking! Though the Sahara is expansive, it is technically is the 3rd largest desert after Antarctica and the Arctic. The Sahara extends from the Atlantic Ocean in the west to the Mediterranean in the north to the Red Sea in the east. There are 10 countries in Africa that have some part of their nation in the Sahara desert. The Sahara has some of the largest sand dunes in the world. Some can reach nearly 600 feet (183 meters) tall. Though movie productions may have convinced us otherwise, only one-fourth of the Sahara terrain is actually comprised of sand dunes. The average temperature in the Sahara is a comfortable 86°F (29°C), but can reach as high as 120°F (49°C) in hottest months of the year.
        If that isn’t hot enough for you, the record temperature was reported at a steamy 136°F (58°C)!</string>
    <string name="thardesert">The Thar Desert is also known as the Great Indian Desert and lies in the northwestern part of India – predominantly in the Royal Rajasthan states. It is the 7th largest sub-tropical desert and the most sparsely populated region in India. Even so, the Thar Desert is the most densely populated desert in the world. Because of the increase in population in the area, the Thar Desert is home to a series of festivals every year which are celebrated with music and dance. The desert is uniquely home to five salt water lakes that mark the landscape.</string>
    <string name="arabiandesert">The Arabian Desert is named after its location as it makes up nearly all of the Arabian Peninsula, which includes the countries of Qatar, Yemen, Oman, United Arab Emirates, Kuwait, and Saudi Arabia. In the center of the Arabian Desert, you will find Earth’s largest area of unbroken sand called Rub’al-Khali. The rest of the desert is made up of gravel plains and rocky hills. It also includes natural occurrences of the notorious and lethal “quicksand.” The Arabian Desert borders the Nile River Valley on its west side and the Gulf of Suez on the eastern end, which makes it essentially surrounded by water on all sides with the exception of the northeast corner that connects it with the Asian continent.</string>
    <string name="kalaharidesert">The Kalahari Desert is unique among the subtropical deserts. It happens to get significantly more rainfall and support more diverse life than its counterparts. It receives nearly double the rainfall (5–9 inches annually) of the Arabian and Sahara desert, yet portions of the Kalahari still meet the definition of a desert in terms of rainfall. It covers most of the African nations of Namibia, Botswana, and portions of South Africa. The Kalahari is approximately 600 miles (966 km) wide and 1,000 miles (1,609 km) north to south. Within the expanse of the Kalahari Desert, you will find the Central Kalahari Game Reserve - the second largest protected area for wildlife in the world.</string>
    <string name="namibdesert">The Namib Desert is classified as a coastal desert and is located in the southern part of Africa. It occupies 1,200 miles (2,000 km) of coastline in the countries of South Africa, Namibia, and Angola. It is widely accepted that the Namib Desert has had a similar arid climate for more than 50 million years, which would make it the oldest desert on Earth. The Namib features gravel plains, mountains, and sand dunes. The sand dunes can grow as high as 1,000 feet tall (302 m) and be more than 15 miles long (30 km). This area is almost entirely unsettled by humans. The Namib Desert gets less than 0.4 inches (10 mm) of rain a year, making it one of the most rain-starved areas in the world!</string>
    <string name="gobidesert">The deserts of the world list would not be complete without the largest desert region in Aisa, the Gobi desert, covering portions of northern and northwestern China and southern Mongolia. As part of the great ancient Mongol Empire (the largest contiguous empire in history) and home to several significant cities along the Silk Road, the Gobi has been one of the more prominent deserts of our history books. The Gobi spans across 500,000 square miles (1,295,000 square kilometers), making it the fifth-largest desert in the world boasting five of its own ecoregions. And due to a process known as desertification, the Gobi continues to expand at an alarming rate. Though the Gobi is home to sand dunes that can be covered in frost or even snow, much of its landscape is actually comprised of exposed bare rock due to winds that whip across the plateau – a far cry from the shifting sands of neighboring Taklamakan desert. The climate of this desert is one of great extremes, characterized by rapid temperature changes – sometimes by as much as 63°F (35°C) in 24 hours!
        The wind of the Siberian Steppes further cause the desert to reach lows of -40°F (-40°C) in winter despite extreme highs of up to 122°F (50°C) in the summer. The Gobi has also been a noteworthy source of significant fossil finds, such as the first discovered dinosaur eggs.</string>
    <string name="desert_definition">Deserts cover about one-third of the Earth’s land surface area. But the deserts of the world are much more than just the sandy, lifeless dunes of storybooks.
        The deserts found on Earth are extremely diverse, each unique in their own way.
        The dunes of the Saharan Desert, the icy tundra of Antarctica, and the Pacific coastline of the Atacama Desert are all deserts.
        That is right; they are all scientifically classified as deserts despite their differences. But it is quite simple,
        really, as they all share one common trait that qualifies them as a desert region: they all receive less than 10 inches (250 mm) of rainfall a year.\n\n Because of the diversity of deserts under this definition,
        they have been split into sub-regions: Sub-Tropical Deserts, Cool Coastal Deserts, Cold Winter Deserts, and Polar Deserts.</string>
    <string name="ocean_definition">The surface of Planet Earth is around 70% water, over 96% of which is salt water. While this vast area is mostly interconnected,
        it is broken up into large and small bodies by the seven continents and other landmasses. The largest of these bodies are known as the Great Oceans.</string>
    <string name="what_is_a_continent_qus">What is a Continent?</string>
    <string name="below_are_continents_of_world">These are the Continents of world.</string>
    <string name="asia_image">Asia Image</string>
    <string name="asia">While Africa is first alphabetically, it is second in both population and size among the Earth’s seven continents. Over 1 billion people can call Africa home.
        The people of Africa are spread across 54 different countries in Africa. This continent is home to 15% of the world’s population and the continent makes up 20% of the total land area on planet earth.
        The equator passes through the center of the continent which provides for largely warm and/or tropical climates. The northern and the southern portion of Africa have more temperate conditions.
        Of the continents of the world, Africa is unique in that it stretches between the northern and southern temperate zones. Africa is also attributed with being the birthplace of mankind.
        The oldest fossil evidence of Homo sapiens was found in the eastern part of the continent. \n\n Africa’s large size and varying climates make it host to many of the most interesting species of plants and animals on Earth.
        There are currently more than 7,000 different species of mammals, fish, and birds in Africa. There are more than 100,000 species of insects as well. Here you can find both the largest ( African Elephant) and tallest (Giraffe) animal.
       \n\nThere are several bodies of water surrounding the continent of Africa. You can find the Indian Ocean to the southeast, the Atlantic Ocean to the west, the Mediterranean Sea to the north and the Red Sea to the northeast.
        \n\nThe continent of Europe and Africa are very close together. They are only 8.9 miles(14.3 km) apart on the northwest corner of Africa. At 4,352 miles long, the Nile River is the longest river in the world and runs along the northeast side of the continent.</string>
    <string name="africa_image">Africa_Image</string>
    <string name="africa">The continent of Antarctica is positioned as the southernmost land mass on Earth.
        The South Pole can be found here among its large permanent glaciers and frigid weather.
        Even though Antarctica has one of the harshest climates and most unwelcoming terrains on planet Earth, there are still nearly five thousand people that temporarily call this continent home every year.
        This makes Antarctica the least populated continent on Earth. Antarctica is known as the coldest landmass and has few native plants or animals because most of the continent is covered in sheets of ice that can be more than a mile thick which forms permanent glaciers.
        You can find penguins, seals, plants, and fungi in Antarctica. Interestingly, this continent is the only one which has no reptiles on its land mass.  \n\nAntarctica is the 5th in terms of size compared to the other 7 continents.
        Both Australia and Europe could fit in the same area that Antarctica covers. The continent is known for being extremely dry which qualifies it as the largest desert region in the world. Antarctica has one of the windiest and coldest climates of the world’s continents.
        Temperatures can reach −90°C (−130 °F) in some regions of the continent.</string>
    <string name="europe_image">Europe_image</string>
    <string name="antarctica">The continent of Antarctica is positioned as the southernmost land mass on Earth. The South Pole can be found here among its large permanent glaciers and frigid weather. Even though Antarctica has one of the harshest climates and most unwelcoming terrains on planet Earth, there are still nearly five thousand people that temporarily call this continent home every year. This makes Antarctica the least populated continent on Earth. Antarctica is known as the coldest landmass and has few native plants or animals because most of the continent is covered in sheets of ice that can be more than a mile thick which forms permanent glaciers. You can find penguins, seals, plants, and fungi in Antarctica. Interestingly, this continent is the only one which has no reptiles on its land mass.  Antarctica is the 5th in terms of size compared to the other 7 continents. Both Australia and Europe could fit in the same area that Antarctica covers. The continent is known for being extremely dry which qualifies it as the largest desert region in the world. Antarctica has one of the windiest and coldest climates of the world’s continents. Temperatures can reach −90°C (−130 °F) in some regions of the continent.</string>
    <string name="europe">The continent of Antarctica is positioned as the southernmost land mass on Earth. The South Pole can be found here among its large permanent glaciers and frigid weather. Even though Antarctica has one of the harshest climates and most unwelcoming terrains on planet Earth, there are still nearly five thousand people that temporarily call this continent home every year. This makes Antarctica the least populated continent on Earth. Antarctica is known as the coldest landmass and has few native plants or animals because most of the continent is covered in sheets of ice that can be more than a mile thick which forms permanent glaciers. You can find penguins, seals, plants, and fungi in Antarctica. Interestingly, this continent is the only one which has no reptiles on its land mass.  Antarctica is the 5th in terms of size compared to the other 7 continents. Both Australia and Europe could fit in the same area that Antarctica covers. The continent is known for being extremely dry which qualifies it as the largest desert region in the world. Antarctica has one of the windiest and coldest climates of the world’s continents. Temperatures can reach −90°C (−130 °F) in some regions of the continent.</string>
    <string name="antarctica_image">Antarctica_image</string>
    <string name="south_america_image">South_america_image</string>
    <string name="south_america">Asia covers nearly 9 percent of the earth’s surface making it the largest of the continents. It is also the home to the most people with an estimated population of 4.3 billion as of 2015 which represents nearly 60% of the world’s population. With this many people, Asia is attributed with being a vital part of the world’s economy. Asia covers nearly 10% of the planet’s surface area and is loosely defined as the eastern portion of the Eurasia continent with the border following a line north from the Aegean Sea to the Black Sea to the NW corner of the Caspian Sea to the Ural River into the Arctic Ocean. The continent is primarily positioned within the northern hemisphere along the eastern portion. On the eastern border, you will find the Pacific Ocean, along the southern border you will find the Indian Ocean, and you can find the Arctic Ocean along the northernmost border.  Asia contains some of the oldest civilizations among the 7 continents including the countries of China and Japan. Asia includes the Saudi Arabia peninsula with the oil-rich countries including the United Arab Emirates and Kuwait. The continent also includes the manufacturing centers of India and Japan and Hong Kong, which is a leading banking and corporate center.</string>
    <string name="australia_image">Australia_image</string>
    <string name="australia">The continent of Australia includes the mainland of the country Australia and the island regions of New Guinea, Tasmania, and Seram. During ice ages, when much of the world’s water was frozen in glaciers, the Australian mainland was connected by land bridges to these islands. Australia is the smallest of the 7 continents but is home to the sixth largest country which is known by the same name, Australia. The continent gets its name from the latin word ‘australis’ which translates to mean southern. As a result of the continent’s geography and size, it is often referred to as an “island” continent. Australia is surrounded by two oceans. The Indian ocean is found on the western side and the pacific ocean is found on the eastern side.  Australia is the most isolated and remote continent of the 7 continents and has been least influenced by migrations of people, plants, and animals. This had led to Australia having a wide variety of animals and plants which are unique in the world such as the kangaroo, koala, dingo, wallaby, and wombat. Of the 5,700 hundred species of animals on the continent of Australia, more than 80% are unique and cannot be found anywhere else in the world. The continent is also home to the world’s largest reef and one of the greatest natural wonders, The Great Barrier Reef.  The continent first was inhabited by man nearly 45,000 years ago. European inhabitants came onto the Australian landmass in the 1700’s. Australia is one of the least populated continents yet the country of Australia is the 12th largest economy in the world.</string>
    <string name="north_america_image">North_America_image</string>
    <string name="north_america">The western portion of the Eurasian landmass is known as Europe. It is noted as one of the smallest of the 7 continents after Australia, with 7 percent of the world’s landmass. However, Europe is home to about 11% of Earth’s population and is the second most densely populated continent, with 134 people per square mile, behind Asia’s 203 people per square mile.  Europe is comprised of approximately 50 countries and several other territories. The country of Russia is the largest country and the area that is occupied by Vatican City in Italy is the smallest. However, Russia has portions of its territory in both the continent of Europe and Asia with forty percent falling in the continent of Europe. Europe, by definition, includes the continental mainland ending in the east at the Ural Mountains in Russia. Europe also includes islands such as Iceland, Sicily, and the British Isles. The British Isles consist of the large island that is home to England, Scotland, and Wales, and is called Great Britain; the British Isles also include the small island that contains Northern Ireland and the Republic of Ireland, and several much smaller surrounding islands.  There are several bodies of water that surround the continent of Europe. To the south, you will find the Mediterranean Sea and the Black Sea, to the west is the Atlantic Ocean, and to the north is the Arctic Ocean.  Europe has played host to many historic events over the course of history that have left a lasting effect and shaped the continent we know today. People have been living in Europe for about 100,000 years. Around 2000 B.C., Indo-European settlers came and brought the language that most modern European languages are descended from. The ancient Greek and Roman civilizations flourished there, from which we get much of our learning and culture. In the 5th and 6th centuries, the Germanic tribes swept over most of Europe, and their descendants shaped the modern countries of Scandinavia and west and central Europe. By this time the Roman empire had become Christian, and eventually, all of Europe became Christian, for reasons of both faith and economics. The diversity and size of Europe led to the continent hosting much of World War I and World War II.</string>
    <string name="click_to_view_contries_of_north_america">Click to view countries of North America</string>
    <string name="click_to_view_contries_of_south_america">Click to view countries of South America</string>
    <string name="click_to_view_contries_of_asia">Click to view countries of Asia</string>
    <string name="click_to_view_contries_of_europe">Click to view countries of Europe</string>
    <string name="click_to_view_contries_of_africa">Click to view countries of Africa</string>
    <string name="click_to_view_contries_of_australia">Click to view countries of Australia</string>
    <string name="click_to_view_contries_of_antarctica">Click to view countries of Antarctica</string>
    <string name="click_on_image_the_to_zoom"><u /> Click on image the to zoom</string>
    <string name="indian_ocean">Indian_ocean</string>
    <string name="indian_ocean_txt">The Indian Ocean covers a 28,400,130 sq mile (73,556,000 km²) area between the eastern coast of Africa, the shores of the Middle East and India to its north, and is separated from the Atlantic Ocean by Southeast Asia and Australia/Oceania. Home to a great variety of humankind throughout history, the Indian Ocean is also rich in exotic plant and animal species, and still supplies the world with spices such as black pepper, nutmeg, and ginger. While these spices are now used primarily to flavor the world’s cuisines, they were used from earliest times to preserve foods, and were thought to have great medicinal properties. Indeed, during the terrible plagues of the 13th through 17th Centuries, Europeans were so convinced of their curative powers that their countries fought repeated wars and gambled untold fortunes to gain control of the Spice Islands, and the number of explorers and sailors willing to risk their lives charting new maps to reach them is difficult to imagine.</string>
    <string name="southern_ocean">Southern_ocean</string>
    <string name="southern_ocean_txt">Until the mid-20th Century, the waters surrounding Antarctica were generally considered to be extensions of the adjoining oceans. But in 2000, members of the International Hydrographic Organization almost unanimously agreed to identify these southernmost waters as the Southern Ocean. Although its definite boundaries are yet to be determined, below 60°S latitude is generally accepted, giving it an area of 7,848,299 sq miles (20,327,000 km²), and making it the fourth largest of the Earth’s oceans. Joining waters of the southern Pacific, Atlantic and Indian Oceans with a persistent easterly current, the frigid Southern Ocean has a great influence on the Earth’s weather patterns.</string>
    <string name="pacific_ocean">Pacific_ocean</string>
    <string name="pacific_ocean_txt">The Pacific is the largest of these oceans, covering 63,784,077 sq miles (165,200,000 km²). It fills the area between the western coastline of the Americas, the eastern coastlines of Asia and Australia, and is capped to the North and South by the Arctic and Antarctic regions. In part because of the numerous tropical islands of East Asia, the Pacific boasts the longest total shoreline, some 84,300 miles (135,663 km). It also holds the deepest point on the earth’s sea floor, the Challenger Deep in the Marianas Trench, near the island of Guam. At close to 11,000 meters below sea level, or almost 7 miles, this crevice was first sounded in 1875 by the HMS Challenger. It would be thought that life forms could not exist at that depth and extreme water pressure. But beginning with radiolarians dredged by the Challenger, hundreds of different species have been found in the Challenger Deep, including shrimp, flatworms, and single-celled protists thought to be very similar to Earth’s earliest life forms. The Pacific was named by Portuguese explorer Ferdinand Magellan, who set sail from Spain in 1519 to find a westerly route to the Spice Islands around the southernmost tip of South America. Rounding the Horn for the first time in November 1520, Magellan passed through the Straits now named for him into a vast sea so calm he described it as a “beautiful, peaceful [pacific] ocean.”</string>
    <string name="arctic_ocean">Arctic_ocean</string>
    <string name="arctic_ocean_txt">At 5,400,025 sq miles (13,986,000 km²), the Arctic is the smallest and shallowest of the five Oceans, and falls mostly within the Arctic Circle. It is surrounded by the Eurasian and North American continents, and includes Hudson Bay and the North and Barents Seas. For most of the year, these seas are a mass of ice often hundreds of feet thick; even during the brief summer months ice can make the Arctic Ocean impassable, and it wasn’t known until modern times that there is little solid ground in the most northern reaches of the Earth. Nonetheless, its icy landscape has been inhabited since ancient times by the hardy ancestors of the Inuit of North America, the Sami of Scandinavia, and the Nenets of Russia. The great explorers of the 16th-19th Centuries were determined to find passage from the North Atlantic through to the rich shores of Asia in search of spices, silks and opium. The majority of these explorations ended in failure and disaster; but in the 19th and 20th Centuries accurate passage was finally charted through the mostly frozen waters of the Arctic.</string>
    <string name="atlantic_ocean">Atlantic_ocean</string>
    <string name="atlantis_ocean_txt">The next largest ocean is the Atlantic, with an area of 41,081,270 sq miles (106,400,000 km²). It is bounded by the Americas to its west, and by the western shores of Europe and Africa to its east. It includes the Mediterranean, Caribbean and Baltic Seas, and the Gulf of Mexico. Like the Pacific Ocean, it reaches to the Arctic and Antarctica. In European History, the Indian and eastern Atlantic Oceans were the most completely charted of the world’s seas until the 15th Century; indeed this area was considered the sum total of the known world. With the escalation of the Spice Trade, desire for a Western route to the East Indies led to the eventual navigation of the globe as we now know it. The warm, stormy waters of the North Atlantic once supported great populations of cod and sperm whale. Cod has been an important human food source for hundreds of years, notably during the founding of America’s colonies, when North American settlements relied heavily upon cod’s easily preserved high-quality flesh. The sperm whale, at over 20 meters in length, is the largest living toothed animal. It has huge stores of bodily oil, used to light the lamps of Europe and North America, made this whale greatly sought-after in the late 18th and early 19th Centuries, nearly leading to its extinction. While high-quality whale oil continued to be used in many industries well into the 20th Century, the development of kerosene meant the end to large-scale sperm whale hunting.</string>
    <string name="images">images</string>
    <string name="continets">Continents</string>
    <string name="oceans">Oceans</string>
    <string name="deserts">Deserts</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main2">Main2Activity</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Android Studio</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">android.studio@android.com</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main">MainActivity</string>
    <string name="menu_home">Home</string>
    <string name="contact_us">Contact Us</string>
    <string name="about_us">About Us</string>
    <string name="rate_us">Rate Us</string>
    <string name="communicate">Communicate</string>
    <string name="share">Share</string>
    <string name="send">Send</string>
    <string name="exit">Exit</string>
    <string name="countory">India</string>


</resources>
